Gerard P. Kuiper papers 1894-1992 (bulk 1949-1973)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series XVII: Slides, 1948–1974.
  - Subseries 2: The slides in this subseries are organized into yellow slide boxes. Slide boxes (folders) 1 through 263 are dated from 1952 to 1974. Slide boxes numbered 263 to 372 are undated. The majority of boxes do have labels. I have done my best to transcribe the labels., April 1965 – May 197
    - Kirk Storch on Mt. Lemon, home gardens; June 1972 (Box 78, Folder 312)
    - Clearing Site III, lichens Bear Canyon; July 11, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 313)
    - Trip to Mt. Lemon, Countess Eleanor Davico; views of garden and backyard; July 15, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 314)
    - Italian TV to Mt. Lemon and site I, San Pedro smelter; lightning struck tree;; summer flowers;; forest fire on Mt. Mica,; July 21, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 315)
    - Front garden and pool in back, August, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 316)
    - Front yard, Sarah leaving for Java, August 6-14, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 317)
    - Front yard after junipers and cypress transplanted, planted blue flowers to celebrate Rosabelle; August–September 1972 (Box 78, Folder 318)
    - The rainy season, front and back yards, rainbow over house; September 1972 (Box 78, Folder 319)
    - Steve Larson’s picture of Haro’s move of 105 crates and telescope, smelter smog east; September 7-15, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 320)
    - Views of front and back yards before dome construction, September 1972 (Box 78, Folder 321)
    - Pommes from study, dome frame; cutting the pommes;; dome construction,; September 1972 (Box 78, Folder 322)
    - Construction of 36 ft. dome on Mt. Lemon, construction of dome interior in my back yard; views of front and back yards,; September 25-27, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 323)
    - Views from Lucy's garden, work on my dome; views of my yard;; flowers pyracantha;; cement work around dome;; Sarah in front of house;; flowers and dome,; October 28, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 324)
    - Mt. Lemon 28” dome construction, sky coronagraph; home dome painting;; Kitt Peak haze;; flight to Flagstaff,; November 8, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 325)
    - Return from Flagstaff, Mt. Lemon pictures; smelter smog,; November 10, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 326)
    - Front garden-fall, dome painted work on adobe; dome and backyard;; Herzbergs leaving;; Tucson Power Plant steam cloud;; Tumamoc in shadow;; Kitt Peak radio and television,; November 12-18, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 327)
    - Baboquivari, Arivaca, Nogales, Mt Hopkins, Mt. Lemon in snow, November 18, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 328)
    - Herzberg visit/Sabino Canyon and Desert Museum, views of home garden and dome; November 1972 (Box 79, Folder 329)
    - Launch Apollo 17 on television with Cronkite, Schirra and Knapp, roses, oranges in front yard; dome backyard;; space experiment on Moon,; December 7-16, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 330)
    - Views of garden, Christmas; December 1972 (Box 79, Folder 331)
    - Garden, to Las Cruces; New Mexico between Lordsburg and Deming; smelter smog,; January 1973 (Box 79, Folder 332)
    - Trip with Sonett to Mt. Lemon, car off the Catalina Highway; good shot of Sonett;; views of garden;; rockets at Huntsville Alabama,; January 31-Feburary 15, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 333)
    - Tankerslee new house on Bear Canyon Creek, front garden at home; dome at sunset;; front palm arch reflected in pool;; Villa de Jardin;; trip to LA;; smog at airport around Tucson;; sand ripples in Colorado;; Mt. Baldy, Mt. Wilson;; LA smog,; February 18-24 (Box 79, Folder 334)
    - Houston LBJ Center, front yard views and back with Laura Wilkening; San Xavier Mission with Laura Wilkening;; baby bowl with pansies;; sleeping circles, Tumamoc,; March 9-24, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 335)
    - de Wiess garden, Tumamoc Basin air; University of Arizona Campus;; Rillito River;; Mt. Hopkins and Mt Wrightson;; Kitt Peak radio fd;; Development on Sierritas,; March 1973 (Box 79, Folder 336)
    - Second trip to Kitt Peak (KPNO), KPNO from 10,500 ft.; Green Valley;; Mt. Hopkins from road;; Mt. Wrightson road;; DM at sunset;; Mt. Lemon at sunset,; April 1973 (Box 79, Folder 337)
    - Back yard roses, 3rd Street orange trees in blossom; trip to NASA-Ames;; Charleston Park, NV;; White Mts. California,; April 1973 (Box 79, Folder 338)
    - Trip to NASA-Ames, Sierra Nevada, Yosemite, Lick; front yard roses sunset,; April 27,1973 (Box 79, Folder 339)
    - Roses front garden and back, trip to Mt. Lemon with Sonett; Mt. Lemon mess hall taken down;; 28” Dome,; Early May 1972 (Box 79, Folder 340)
    - At de Wiesses’ interiors, Lucy and Rosabelle in pool (de-Wiess); Lucy and Rosabelle at home;; Jean Marc leaves for San Francisco,; July 28 – August, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 341)
    - Lucy and Rosabelle depart for California, August 7, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 342)
    - Lucy's garden, Mt. Lemon; Evans house,; September 22, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 343)
    - Mt. Lemon, trip to Houston and return; Mt. Graham and Mt. Lemon smog pictures; garden;; visit to Dale Cruikshank,; October 12-15,1973 (Box 79, Folder 344)
    - Mt. Lemon in smog from east, Douglas smelter, clouds over Monterrey, Mexico; Velasco Palace/pueblo,; [October 1973] (Box 79, Folder 345)
    - Puebla –Acapulco, October 19-21, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 346)
    - Atlixtac, to mountain road, tuff deposits, tuff deposits; Carrasco-Calle Socrates Nursery;; leaving Chilpancingo, back Hacienda;; back at Puebla Hotel del Angel Tonantzintla,; [October 1973] (Box 79, Folder 347)
    - Trip to Madison and Yerkes, return via Lake Como Geneva; some pictures after return to Tucson,; November 8-11, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 348)
    - Garden Tucson, November 1973 (Box 79, Folder 349)
    - Garden Tucson, December 1973 (Box 79, Folder 350)
    - Pictures by Paul; pictures of Kuiper’s office, December 25, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 351)
    - Smog below 4000 ft., Smog from Windy Point; Panoramic view from building on Mt. Lemon;; Ski Lodge;; 40" dome on Solider Peak (what's left);; San Pedro Valley,; [October 31-November 7, 1973] (Box 79, Folder 352)
    - Paul and Diana, Rosabelle’s birthday Java, Jakarta; May-August 20, 1974 (Box 79, Folder 353)
    - Bali trip (Mrs. Kuiper), October 1974 (Box 79, Folder 354)
  - Subseries 3: In this subseries the slides are organized by date.
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1958; 1969-1970 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Jupiter, [1967-1970] (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Observations, 1970-1973 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Work related, January – December 1971 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Work related, October – December 1972 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Work related, March – May 1973 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Mexico trip, December 1973 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - NASA 990 Solar Spectra, Oregon craters, no date (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4: The slides in this subseries are not dated and are organized by subject
    - Alphonsus Crater (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Kuiper family slides (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Mount Lemon (best slides) (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Personal and scenic (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Plitvicka Jezera (Plitvice Lakes), Croatia (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Solar System v.1 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Solar System v.2 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Texas color slides (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Trip to Russia (includes guide for slides) (Box 81, Folder 9)
- Series XVIII: Audio tapes, one filmstrip and films
  - Subseries 1: Audio tapes and one film-strip, this subseries is organized by date, 1965-1973
    - 35th Ranger Mission, April 4, 1965 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Address by G.P. Kuiper at Lowell Observatory, May 5, 1965 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Dedication of the Science Building and symposium - A, January 26-28, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Dedication of the Science Building and symposium - B, January 26-28, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Dedication of the Science Building and symposium - C, January 26-28, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Dedication of the Science Building and symposium - D, January 26-28, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Dedication of the Science Building and symposium - E, January 26-28, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - The Lunar Surface”, Lecture by G.P. Kuiper, March 20, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - “Origin of the Moon and Planets” lecture and discussion by Dr. Kuiper, February 15, 1973 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Gerard Kuiper Memorial Service, Unitarian Church, December 30, 1973 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Dr. Kuiper talking about Jupiter and 2 home movies – A, no date (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - Dr. Kuiper talking about Jupiter and 2 home movies featuring Kuiper – B, no date (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - Dr. Kuiper talking about Jupiter and 2 home movies featuring Kuiper – C, no date (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - Filmstrip - Op de Sterrenwacht, no date (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - Radio interview with G.P. Kuiper, sound only in Dutch, 4 minutes, no date (Box 81, Folder 24 -)
  - Subseries 2: Films
    - Celestial pictures taken by the TV Telescope, produced by Space Surveillance Division, Air Force Missile Test Center Cape Canaveral, black and white, no sound, 20 minutes. Survey of lunar surface, pictures of Saturn and Jupiter., 1961 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Lunar Bridgehead Flight of Ranger” produced by Irl Newlan, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, black and white with sound, 30 minutes. NASA film clip about the 1964 Ranger 7 mission to the Moon. Describes the launch cameras, flight, and impact on the Moon. Features H. Newell, W. Pickering, E. Shoemaker and E. Whitaker. Excerpts of the 2nd press conference at JPL. Gerard Kuiper analyzes the first lunar photos. The DVD is included with this film. (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Ranger 7 photographs of the Moon, Camera A Series,produced by NASA/JPL black and white with sound, 6 minutes, August 28, 1964 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Interview with G.P. Kuiper, black and white, with sound, 8 minutes. Includes Kuiper’s description of the lunar surface and first ranger photos, production of the lunar atlas, and the possibility of life on Mars. CBS Broadcasting, Inc.DVD is included with the film, no date (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Interview with Kuiper, black and white, with sound in Dutch, 15 minutes. Pictures of Tucson and the University of Arizona in the 1960’s. Kuiper discusses lunar geology. (Box 83a, Folder 1)
    - De Leidsche Sterrewacht, 1633-1944 produced by Multi film, Haarlem, black and white, no sound, 10 minutes. Pictures of the Le Leiden Observatory, including daily life. Features Hertzsprund, de Sitter and Oort. (Box 83a, Folder 2)
    - 3. Verover de Aarde, Vandaag de Maan van Prof. G. Kuiper, Dutch documentary film, black and white, with sound (mostly in Dutch), 35 minutes. Excerpts from the NASA film “Lunar Bridgehead.” Includes pictures of Tucson, the University of Arizona, Mt. Bigelow, the lunar atlas, and the Ranger photos of the Moon (black and white) with sound mostly in Dutch,., 1633-1944 (Box 83a, Folder 3)
    - Kuiper footage, black and white, some of the sound is in Dutch, 14 minutes. Kuiper discusses the Lunar Orbiter, lunar surface, lunar atlas, and Mars, no date (Box 83b, Folder 4)
    - Home movies featuring G.P. Kuiper. Color, no sound, 24 minutes. Kuiper ridding in a car, doing observations, in garden, in office being interviewed, no date (Box 83b, Folder 5)
    - Ranger 8 television pictures of the moon” produced by JPL, Black and white, with Sound, 7 minutes. Pictures from last 23 minutes of the flight to impact on the Moon on 2/20/65. Last 40 pictures taken by the A and B cameras. Also last P channel pictures., June 1965 (Box 83b, Folder 6)
    - 1. Face the issues – KTKT radio dub – I side, 2 tracks, undated; Films, 1 DVD, 3 Magnetic Recording tapes (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Uranus and Netune – Lecture Dr. G.P. Kuiper, March 20, 1967 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - 3.Audio recordings of Dr. Kuiper Side1: Excerpts from an Air force radio program aired, August 2, 1964. Narrator T/Sgt Bill Hickinbotham, USAF program titled; Background-Ranger VII “L + 6”. Side 2: Ranger IX News conference. (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Dedication Speeches – Mauna Kea Station, 1964 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - 1 7/8 recordings by Thornton Page, Johnson Space Center, Houston, Texas 77058 Memories of Gerard P. Kuiper, February 9, 1974 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - DVD - Kuiper Audio Recordings - LPL Archive Audio files, undated (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - 3 Magnetic recording tapes – Haleakala Report, undated (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Untitled film, undated (Box 84, Folder 8)